## Lynda Foster

lyndabrf@gmail.com | Phone | Github | LinkedIn | Burbank, CA

#### **SUMMARY**

Cloud Engineer with a BS Computer Science, a specialization in Salesforce technologies, and a background in DevOps.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Java | React | SQL | Python | Bash

**Web/API:** JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Regex | Postman | Swagger | XML **DevOps:** AWS | Terraform | Jenkins | Ansible | Kubernetes | Ubuntu | Docker

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Salesforce - San Francisco, CA | Developer Support Engineer | 05/2023 - Present

- Provide subject matter expertise for GovCloud applications
- Created and maintained systems documentation for support processes and procedures
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to identify and resolve client issues

Environment: Apex, Visualforce, Splunk, Workbench, Delphi, Blacktab, VS Code, Python, SQL, Tableau

Smoothstack - McLean, VA (Remote) | Cloud Engineer | 11/2022 - 04/2023

- Worked within an Agile Scrum team to deploy a highly scalable, available, and fault-tolerant 3-tier web application using sprints, code review, peer programming, and retrospectives
- Produced code that adheres to established security standards and quality control protocols using the Atlassian Suite (JIRA/Confluence) and Git Flow
- Architected reusable infrastructure modules with Terraform and Ansible to deploy applications to Amazon Web Services (ECS and EKS)
- Executed cost-benefit analysis of tech stack and proposed new software architecture that incorporated **CloudWatch** implementation, resulting in improved cost-monitoring
- Supported and maintained monitoring and alert systems with ELK stack and CloudWatch
- Designed and maintained a robust CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins and GitLab to streamline the deployment of Java Spring Boot microservices, React/Angular UI, and MySQL database to AWS
- Developed gray box smoke tests using Python for Java Spring Boot microservices to validate basic functionality before integration into a CI/CD pipeline
- Automated service operations and application installation using Python and Bash scripts

Environment: AWS, Terraform, Ansible, Jenkins, Kubernetes (EKS), CloudWatch, Splunk, ELK, GitLab, Python, Bash, Agile Scrum, JIRA, Confluence

Vermont Idea Company - Shelburne, VT (Remote) | Systems Software Engineer | 10/2022 - 03/2023

- Maintained and managed systems documentation in Confluence and Software Design Document
- Implemented and converted existing MATLAB scripts to Python, adjusting the architecture to conform to an object-oriented programming environment
- Analyzed algorithm performance, identified opportunities for optimization and efficiency improvements, and proposed solutions

Environment: Python, MATLAB, Confluence, Jira, XML

# **Lynda Foster**

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Terraform Associate (002) | Splunk Core Power User | Axelos ITIL Foundation

## **EDUCATION**

MSc in Data Analytics | Western Governors University | Salt Lake City, UT BSc in Computer Science & Accounting | Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT